<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intros on cobrapy - constraint-based metabolic modeling in Python</title>
    <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intros on cobrapy - constraint-based metabolic modeling in Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/description/</guid>
      <description>cobrapy is a python package that provides a simple interface to metabolic constraint-based reconstruction and analysis.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import cobra &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; model = cobra.io.read_sbml_model(&#39;Ec_core_flux1.xml&#39;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; model.metabolites[:3] [&amp;lt;Metabolite 13dpg_c at 0x112b2d160&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;Metabolite 2pg_c at 0x1024eb048&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;Metabolite 3pg_c at 0x112b2d748&amp;gt;]  The package includes simple, object-oriented interfaces for model construction (including reading to/from sbml, matlab, and json formats) and implements commonly used COBRA methods such as flux balance analysis, flux variability analysis, and gene deletion analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/installation/</guid>
      <description>You can install cobrapy on linux, Mac OSX and Windows with pip.
On Linux and Mac a simple:
$ pip install cobra  will be enough. On Windows substitute pip with pip.exe.
If you want to install all optional dependencies as well just install with
$ pip install cobra[all]  For futher help refer to the detailed installation instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Help</title>
      <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/intro/help/</guid>
      <description>The documentation is browsable online at readthedocs and can also be downloaded.
Please use the Google Group for help. Alternatively, you can use gitter.im for quick questions and discussions about cobrapy (faster response times).
File bug reports and contribute to development on our github page.
If you use cobrapy in a scientific publication, please cite our publication 😄</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>