<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>micobiome on cobrapy - constraint-based metabolic modeling in Python</title>
    <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/tags/micobiome/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in micobiome on cobrapy - constraint-based metabolic modeling in Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/tags/micobiome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>micom</title>
      <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/packages/micom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 11:52:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/packages/micom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;micom is a Python package for metabolic modeling of microbial communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;micom allows you to construct a community model from a list on input COBRA
models and manages exchange fluxes between individuals and individuals with the
environment. It explicitly accounts for different abundances of individuals in
the community and can thus incorporate data from 16S rRNA sequencing
experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mminte</title>
      <link>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/packages/mminte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 11:00:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opencobra.github.io/cobrapy/packages/mminte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MMinte (pronounced /‘minti/) is an integrated pipeline that allows users to explore the pairwise interactions (positive or negative) that occur in a microbial network. From an association network and 16S rDNA sequence data, MMinte identifies corresponding genomes, reconstructs metabolic models, estimates growth under specific metabolic conditions, analyzes pairwise interactions, assigns interaction types to network links, and generates the corresponding network of interactions. Our application is composed of seven widgets that run sequentially, and each widget may also be run as independent modules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>